hey guys this looks like a fun one these
A's and B's are placeholders so this
doesn't mean a * a it means some
matching double digit number like 22 or
33 now we're trying to solve for A and B
so that this plus this equals this we
probably could guess and check but I
want to see if we can figure it out
logically since the a plus b gives us a
three in the one spot we know that
either a plus b = 3 or a plus b = 13
let's explore these possibilities if a
plus b equals 3 that means this a plus
this B would be 3 and then in the 10
place the a plus b would also give us a
three in the 10's place in this case
nothing will carry over so in the
hundred's place we have a zero but we
know from up here the hundred's place
needs to have a one so it is not
possible for a plus b to equal 3 so we
know for sure that a plus b is equal to
13 so that means when we do a plus b
we're going to be carrying a one for the
10's place and now let's focus on the
10's column this one represents 10 this
a represents 10 a this B represents 10 B
and then we're going to add all those
together and set it equal to this 1
which represents 100 plus this a which
represents 10 a and now we want to solve
this system of equations let's subtract
10 from both sides and let's subtract 10
a from both sides on the left hand side
this stuff all cancels out so we just
have 10 B and on the right hand side
have 90 after we divide both sides by 10
we get B is equal to 9 and that's
important so let's put a box around it
and then let's copy down this a plus b =
13 and let's substitute 9 for this B
after we subtract 9 from both sides we
get a is equal to 4 and let's put a box
around that so now we have an answer a
equal 4 and b equal 9 let's check our
work let's change this AA into 44 and
let's change this a down here into a
four and then the BB we can change into
99 and we have 4 + 9 is equal to 3 carry
a 1 1 + 4 + 9 is 14 so this checks out
so a does equal 4 and B does equal 9 how
exciting